EMMANUEL EZEKIEL

emmanuelezekiel228@gmail.com • +234 (813) 561-0471

http://www.linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-ezekiel • https://github.com/emmanuel-ezekiel • https://emmanuel-ezekiel.github.io/Personal-website

Summary

I'm a Frontend Developer with bachelor's in physics with experience developing web applications with a deep understanding of effective team collaboration, Skilled and persistent problem solver who writes clean, elegant code and with a deep knowledge of Agile methodology and scrum operations. Demonstrated ability to collaborate effectively on project delivery across all phases of the software lifecycle including requirements management, customisation, programming, testing, and deployment.

Skills

React • JavaScript • HTML/CSS • Git • Node.js • Github • TypeScript • Redux

Work Experience

Frontend Developer Jul 2021 – present

AFTj Digitals And Marketing • Full-time

Remote

Technologies: JavaScript • React • Redux • HTML/CSS • Github

- Developed reusable components, front end libraries and new user facing features using ReactJs.
- Tested, coded, reviewed, and delivered software with 100% on-time record and according to service level objectives
- Designed and implemented Command Line Interface that accomplishes all the important tasks for React development such as setting up the development environment, generating a new project. This CLI tool reduced developers' onboarding time to React js by 80%

Frontend developer

Feb 2020 - Jul 2020 • 5 mos

The RootHub • Internship

Uyo, Akwa-Ibom State, Nigeria

Technologies: JavaScript • HTML/CSS • Bootstrap • Git • Github

- Ensured quality standards for accessibility, performance, and code cleanliness through unit testing and peer review
- Designed and developed new custom components to meet project requirements.
- Contributed new tools to internal development libraries

Projects

work Remotely https://we-work-remotely.netlify.app/

Sep 2021 – present

Technologies: React • HTML5 • CSS3

• The purpose of the website is to help employers to embrace diversity, equity, and inclusion as fundamental values when hiring through Work Remotely.

Food Delivery https://food-delivery-webpage.netlify.app/

May 2021 – Jul 2021 • 2 mos

Technologies: JavaScript • HTML5 • Sass/css

- · Website Delivery.
- Compatible with all mobile devices and with a beautiful and pleasant user interface.

Educations

Bachelor's degree: Physics

Jun 2014 - Oct 2018 • 4 yrs 4 mos

University Of Uyo

Uyo, Akwa-Ibom State., Nigeria